Guide to the Leroy E. Burney Papers
Yale University Library
- WRITINGS, 1937-1963, no date; Series II; 3' (8 boxes)
  - "Emerging Profiles in Total Health Care," Journal of the American Dental Association: speech text, reprint, correspondence and background material, 1963 Mar-Jul, 1964 Jan, Jul (Box 26, Folder 151)
  - "Changing Profiles": speech text, correspondence and program, 1963 Apr-Jun (Box 26, Folder 152)
  - Conference on Medical Education for Foreign Scholars in the Medical Sciences: correspondence, programs and background material, 1963 May-Jul (Box 26, Folder 153)
  - Needed—A Fresh Approach: speech text, 1963 Nov (Box 26, Folder 154)
  - Mobilizing Resources—A Fresh Approach: speech text, 1964 Mar (Box 26, Folder 155)
  - "Diagnosis, Prognosis and Treatment": edited speech transcript, ca. 1964 Mar (Box 26, Folder 156)
  - "How to Keep Your Family Healthy": speech text, 1964 Apr (Box 26, Folder 157)
  - "The Professional Environment: Scientific Knowledge, Technical Application and Fiscal Support": speech text and correspondence, 1964 Jul-1965 Apr (Box 26, Folder 158)
  - "Profile of Medicine for the 1968 Graduate": speech text, 1964 Sep (Box 26, Folder 159)
  - "Progress of the National Commission on Community Health Services": speech text and background material, 1964 Oct (Box 26, Folder 160)
  - "Implications for Comprehensive Health Care," Milbank Memorial Fund Quarterly: reprint, 1964 Oct (Box 26, Folder 161)
  - "Statement," Philadelphia Zoning Board of Adjustment: text, 1964 Oct 6 (Box 26, Folder 162)
  - "Remarks," dinner honoring Dr. I. S. Ravdin: text, 1965 Mar 4 (Box 26, Folder 163)
  - "Remarks," General Electric Occupational Health Conference: speech outline, correspondence and background material, 1965 Mar-Nov (Box 26, Folder 164)
  - "Remarks," American Association for the History of Medicine: text, 1965 Apr 30 (Box 26, Folder 165)
  - "Reaching Out for New Dimensions," Milbank Memorial Fund Quarterly: reprint, speech text (fragment) and draft, 1965 Sep, 1966 Jul, no date (Box 26, Folder 166)
  - "The University and Community Health Services: The Fifth Annual Bronfman Lecture," American Journal of Public Health: reprints, speech text and related draft, 1965 Oct, 1966 Mar, May (Box 26, Folder 167)
  - ["Forecast for Health Care and Medical Practice"?]:draft, 1965? (Box 26, Folder 168)
  - "Exploration, Expansion and Expectation": speech text, correspondence and draft material, 1966 Jan-Oct (Box 26, Folder 169)
  - Panel discussion remarks, Council on Foundations: outline, transcript (fragment), correspondence and background material, 1966 Feb-Jun (Box 26, Folder 170)
  - "Health and Disease," Science Year: script, correspondence and related material, 1966 Apr (Box 26, Folder 171)
  - "Evolving Health and Medical Practice: The Eighth Annual John Franklin Huber Lecture," Journal of Phi Rho Sigma: reprint, 1966 May (Box 26, Folder 172)
  - "A Moving Target": speech drafts, correspondence and related material, 1966 Aug-1967 Apr (Box 26, Folder 173)
  - "Dirty Air is Dangerous Air": speech text, draft and correspondence, 1966 Sep-Oct (Box 27, Folder 174)
  - A New Era—The Delivery of Health Care Services: speech drafts, notes and related material, 1967 Jan (Box 27, Folder 175)
  - Meeting with Mayor Tate: notes and comment, 1967 Feb 10 (Box 27, Folder 176)
  - "Changing Social Scene: Its Impact on the Health Care System": speech drafts, summary and correspondence, 1967 Mar Nov (Box 27, Folder 177)
  - "Blue Ribbon Panel to Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller on Municipal Hospitals of New York City": report, 1967 Apr (Box 27, Folder 178)
  - "Standing Together": speech text and background material, 1967 Apr (Box 27, Folder 179)
  - "Medicare: The Problems and the Promises": speech text and newsclipping, 1967 May (Box 27, Folder 180)
  - "Recognition of the Hospital Infections Problem": speech drafts, notes and correspondence, 1967 May-Jun (Box 27, Folder 181)
  - "Report of Consultants to Special Advisory Committee on Charity Hospital of New Orleans": report, 1967 Aug (Box 27, Folder 182)
  - "New Developments in Urban Health Planning: The Philadelphia Story": speech texts and correspondence, 1967 Aug-Sep (Box 27, Folder 183)
  - "Philadelphia's Health Progress": speech drafts and correspondence, 1967 Sep-Oct (Box 27, Folder 184)
  - "The Christian Physician and Tomorrow's Society": speech text and correspondence, 1967 Nov 14-16 (Box 27, Folder 185)
  - The Rationale for Area Wide Hospital Planning "Conversations" series, ARA Hospital Food Management: pamphlet, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 186)
  - "Impact Forces on Rising Costs of Health Care and Health Care Facilities": speech drafts, correspondence and related material, 1967 Dec-1968 Jan (Box 27, Folder 187)
  - Medical Facilities Seminar: speech draft, correspondence and related material, 1968 Jan-Jun (Box 27, Folder 188)
  - "The Christian Physician and Tomorrow's Society": speech text and correspondence, 1968 Feb, Oct (Box 27, Folder 189)
  - "The Hospital as a Community Health Center": speech notes, outline and correspondence, 1968 Mar (Box 27, Folder 190)
  - Untitled speech re: consumer and health care, National Health Forum: speech text and draft, 1968 Mar (Box 27, Folder 191)
  - "Air Pollution: A Community Health Forum," Transactions and Studies of the College of Physicians of Philadelphia: reprint, 1968 Apr (Box 27, Folder 192)
  - "Health is a Community Affair": speech notes, summary and correspondence, 1968 Apr-Aug (Box 27, Folder 193)
  - "Planning for Comprehensive Health Care at Temple University Hospital," Public Health Reports: reprint, 1968 Jun (Box 27, Folder 194)
  - "Planning Process in Health": speech drafts and correspondence, 1968 Jun-Oct (Box 27, Folder 195)
  - Untitled manuscript re: professional schools: text, 1968 Jul (Box 27, Folder 196)
  - "Past Accomplishments as Indicators of Future Potential": speech drafts and correspondence, 1968 Aug-Sep 1969 Apr (Box 27, Folder 197)
  - "Health Education in a Changing World": speech text, draft and correspondence, 1969 Jul-1970 Feb (Box 28, Folder 198)
  - "New Missions in Health Service: To Act or React," The Journal of School Health: reprint, speech text and background material, 1969-1970 (Box 28, Folder 199)
  - "The Role of Foundations in Voluntarism": speech text and correspondence, 1970 May-Jun (Box 28, Folder 200)
  - "New Agenda": speech text and correspondence, 1970 Nov (Box 28, Folder 201)
  - "Agenda for Change, Past and Future of the Milbank Memorial Fund": text of essay prepared from speech notes, 1970 Dec 16-19 (Box 28, Folder 202)
  - "A New Agenda and a New Alliance," Bulletin of the New York Academy of Medicine: reprint, 1971 Mar (Box 28, Folder 203)
  - "Critical Decisions in Health Care and the Role of Foundations": speech text, 1971 Apr 30 (Box 28, Folder 204)
  - "Some Critical Issues Relating to the Physician's Assistant": speech text, correspondence and background material, 1971 Apr-May (Box 28, Folder 205)
  - Remarks, Medical Education and Medical Care--A Dynamic Equilibrium? text and correspondence, 1971 Sep-Nov (Box 28, Folder 206)
  - "Unity in the Preservation and Improvement of Health": speech text, correspondence and photograph, 1972 Jan-May (Box 28, Folder 207)
  - "From Community Hospital to Community Health Center": speech texts, correspondence and program, 1972 May-Sep (Box 28, Folder 208)
  - "Bringing Knowledge into Contact with People": speech texts, correspondence and newsclippings, 1973 Feb-Jul (Box 28, Folder 209)
  - "Some Perceptions and Perspectives on Health Problems and Needs": speech text and background material, 1976 Mar (Box 28, Folder 210)
  - Miscellaneous background material for writing speeches, 1940-1966, no date (Box 28, Folder 211)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence re: speeches, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 212)
  - Untitled manuscript re: health care delivery: text, no date (Box 28, Folder 213)
  - "The Hospital, Its Nature and Functions": chapter outlines, concepts and chapter II drafts, no date (Box 28, Folder 214)
  - Land of the Queen of Sheba": speech text, no date (Box 28, Folder 215)
  - "Self Medication and Community Health": abstract, manuscript and related draft, no date (Box 28, Folder 216)
  - "The Veteran's Health": speech text, no date (Box 28, Folder 217)
  - "The Veterinary Public Health": text of statement, no date (Box 28, Folder 218)
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILES, 1945-1976; Series III; 0.25 linear feet (1 box)
  BIOGRAPHICAL FILES is arranged chronologically.
  - Photographs, ca. 1945-1955, 1969, no date (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Biographical sketches, curriculum vitae and passport, 1953-1956, 1975-1977, no date (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Newsclippings and related material, 1956, 1968-1976 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Distinguished Service Award, 1961 Apr (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Personal and family correspondence, 1969-1977 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Royal Society of Medicine: correspondence and membership application, 1971 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Who's Who in America: correspondence, galley proofs and related material, 1973-1977 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Sedgwick Memorial Award: correspondence, press releases and speech text (Burney), 1975-1976 (Box 29, Folder 8)